themail.com 2000-10-18

# Privacy Policy

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to TheMail.com by e-mail to [privacy@themail.com](mailto:privacy@themail.com). 

**Overview**

At TheMail.com, we respect your privacy. We do collect information from you, but it is our policy and priority to ensure that all personal information remains private and secure. To earn your trust and confidence in the Internet and in TheMail.com, we are disclosing our privacy practices and the uses of the information we gather. 

To protect your privacy, TheMail.com: 

  * TheMail.com will not intentionally monitor or disclose any private e-mail message to third parties unless required by law, regulation, court order, or legitimate administrative purpose. 
  * Will not knowingly use personal identifying information from children younger than 18 without parental consent 

These links provide detailed information on our privacy practices:   

  1. What general information does TheMail.com collect and how is it used?
  2. What personal information does TheMail.com collect and how is it used?
  3. What are cookies and how does TheMail.com use them?
  4. How do third-party advertisers use my information?
  5. How does TheMail.com protect the privacy of children younger than 18?
  6. How can I access, change or delete information about myself?
  7. How may I protect my privacy on the Internet and within TheMail.com?

TheMail.com reserves the right to amend this Privacy Statement at any time without prior notice, and only the current Privacy Statement may be deemed effective. 

**1\. What _general_ information does TheMail.com collect about me and how is it used?**   
When you visit TheMail.com, we collect some basic information about your computer, such as: 

  * IP address (your computer's unique signature)
  * Operating system (eg: Windows 2000)
  * Browser software (eg: Microsoft Internet Explorer, Netscape)
  * Internet Service Provider (eg: AOL, Mindspring, etc...)
  * Other numeric codes used to identify a computer

The information we collect is aggregated to reflect the population as a whole rather than focused on individuals. We use it to help us better understand the people who visit TheMail.com. In addition, like many other sites with paid advertising, we disclose some of this aggregate information to advertisers to inform them of the number of people who have seen and clicked on their advertisements. 

**2\. What _personal_ information does TheMail.com collect about me and how is it used?**   
During the TheMail.com signup process, we ask you to supply personal information. We also ask if you would like to receive promotional material from our sponsors and great offers from our service partners. 

Once you are a member, TheMail.com may ask you to update your personal information from time to time. We use this information to personalize our services which include e-mail, calendar, member surveys, and customer service. We also use this information, in aggregate, to better target advertising banners and make the content more relevant to each member. 

**Communication**   
As a new member, you will find a welcome letter waiting for you when you first log into your new mailbox. 

Established members will receive: 

  * **A periodic gift.** Occasionally, we are able to offer you some really great deals from companies offering free gifts, services or coupons. We pass these gifts on to you.
  * **A periodic newsletter and service announcements.** The newsletter contains general information about your e-mail account and interesting news from the internet. The service announcements contain information regarding updates to our services, features, or products. Newsletters are mailed not more than once per week. Members are not able to unsubscribe from the newsletter or service announcements. 

If you do not log in for a prolonged period of time, we may use your alternate e-mail address and home address to insure that you receive important news about your TheMail.com account or other information that you have requested. 

TheMail.com cooperates with law enforcement agencies to identify those who use our services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to release information about members who we believe are in violation of our user agreement, even without a subpoena, warrant or court order. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we reasonably believe to be unlawful. 

**Credit Cards**   
If you sign up for premium services, TheMail.com will use your credit card number in order to provide you with the services that you request. Information collected by TheMail.com is encrypted using SSL technology and is stored on secure servers. Credit card transactions are processed by an established financial institution. Access to credit card information at TheMail.com is restricted to authorized staff only, in a manner consistent with or exceeding industry standards. 

Remember that third-party vendors also sell products and services via advertising on TheMail.com and their policies may differ from those of TheMail.com. 

**3\. What are cookies and how does TheMail.com use them?**   
TheMail.com requires each member to enable cookies to login and use our services. 

**What is a Cookie?**   
A cookie is a very small text file placed on your hard drive - with your permission - by a web server. 

**Why do we use Cookies?**   
_Identification:_ We use cookies to identify you uniquely. For example, this allows us to pre-populate your e-mail address on the login page. 

_Tracking and Maintaining Session info:_ Once you have logged in, we use the cookie to distinguish between your mail session and that of the many other people using our service. For example: After you have written a message and you go to your Inbox, we need to display your Inbox and not somebody else's. Setting cookies is currently the best method of maintaining session information over the web. TheMail.com may allow advertisers or partners to set cookies, however, only if they agree to abide by our privacy rules and policies. 

**Are cookies secure?**   
A cookie cannot contain program code, so it cannot be used as a virus nor can it be used to extract data from your system. When a cookie is set, only the server which set the cookie can access the information in that cookie. The use of cookies allows TheMail.com to provide a higher level of security for your e-mail account. 

**How do I change the way my browser handles cookies?**   
Most browsers allow three options for handling cookies: 

  * Accept all cookies
  * Warn before accepting a cookie
  * Reject all cookies

Our web-based mail service will not function unless your browser is set to accept cookies. Instructions for enabling and disabling cookies can be found through the help menu on most browsers. If you have continued trouble changing your cookie settings, you may contact our support site for additional help. 

**4\. How do third-party advertisers use my information?**   
We may share some of your information such as name and e-mail address with third party sponsors. In addition, you may at the time of sign up and during subsequent use of our services, request to receive information from select third party sponsors. This information is a good way to learn about special offers on the web. 

You may request that e-mail be sent to your TheMail.com account containing promotional offers, editorial content, or calendar reminders at any time. If you have requested such e-mail and you have not logged into your account for a prolonged period of time, we may forward the requested information to your alternate e-mail address. 

All promotional e-mails that you request through TheMail.com will include a removal procedure which will allow you to discontinue receiving further e-mail offers. i.e., you can change your mind about receiving further e-mails at a later date. 

If you receive an e-mail from a third party stating that it is associated with TheMail.com, yet you do not recall asking for the information, please follow the third party's removal procedures. If this procedure is not successful, please forward the e-mail with a summary of your experience to [privacy@themail.com](mailto:privacy@themail.com). 

Additionally, be aware that when you click on ad banners, you may be brought to other sites not operated by TheMail.com. You are responsible for information you provide these sites. We recommend that you review the privacy policy of any site that requests personal information. 

**5\. How does TheMail.com protect the privacy of children younger than 18?**   
We believe that it's especially important to protect children's privacy online. 

TheMail.com does ask that children under 18 get their parent's permission to sign up for a new account. We administrate this by asking the parent to click on a box saying it's O.K. for the child to use the service after entering their registration information. 

All general information collected from children is used only for statistical analysis, feedback and those purposes described in the signup process. We actively block the transmission of children's personal information to advertising third parties, regardless of whether children request promotional opportunities through us. 

There are a number of emerging standards in the area of children's privacy that will affect how we process a child's profile information in the future. 

**6\. How do I access, change or delete information about myself?**   
Your personal information can be accessed, or changed by selecting "Preferences" then "Personal Info" in the navigation bar on the left, once you are logged in. 

**7\. How may I protect my privacy on the Internet and within TheMail.com?**

  1. **Know the risks.**   
If you provide your e-mail address to public domains such as chat rooms or newsgroups, or you provide it to websites which don't respect your privacy, you may begin to receive unsolicited e-mail. Unsolicited e-mail is also known as spam. Although TheMail.com has strict rules prohibiting spam and we do block certain known groups from sending unsolicited messages to TheMail.com members, it is generally a good idea to provide your e-mail address only to people or groups that you trust. 
  2. **Educate yourself.**   
Look for a privacy statement on every site you visit on the Web, and search for information on how to protect your privacy. 
  3. **Tell your children: "Never talk to strangers!"**   
Teach children not to give out their names or other personal information. Tell them never to fill out online registration forms without your knowledge and consent. 
  4. **Use complex passwords.**   
If your password is simple, it is also simple for a hacker to break it and gain access to your e-mail account or other private areas. To protect your privacy, you should use complex passwords consisting of very long and awkward keystroke combinations. This makes the hacker's job much more difficult. 

We send reminders of your account passwords only after the appropriate security questions have been answered. NEVER GIVE YOUR PASSWORD TO ANYONE. If someone claiming to represent TheMail.com in an e-mail or chat room asks for your TheMail.com password, DO NOT RESPOND. The only time we ask for your password is via a web page, when you need to access our system (such as the login screen). Please help us keep our records current by updating your personal information when it changes. You can access your personal information by selecting "My Account, Personal Information" from the navigation bar on the left, when you're logged into your account. 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. Our third-party advertising company also separately places or recognizes a cookie file on your browser in the course of delivering advertisements to this Site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please [click here](http://www.sonar.com/content/privacy.htm). 

You agree to be bound by all of its terms and conditions of this Privacy Statement. 

In the event of any discrepancy between the TheMailProgram Terms of Use, and any FAQs, Privacy Statement, and similar statement posted by Themail.com, the terms of the Terms Of Use shall control.
